avadirect.com 2017-10-05

# Privacy & Security Policy | AVADirect

## Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Freedom USA, Inc., dba AVADirect.com ("AVADirect," "we", or "us") collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User," or "you") of the AVADirect.com website ("Site"). By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. 

### Personally identifiable information

We collect personally identifiable information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, register on the site, fill out a form, purchase goods or services, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, phone number, and other information. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously.

We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information; however, refusing to provide personally identifiable information may prevent a User from engaging in certain Site-related activities.

### Other information

We automatically collect other information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. This automatically collected information may include the browser name, the type of computer, the IP address, the domains from which Users are referred to the Site, and technical information about a User's means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

### Web browser cookies

We want to allow for you to quickly find information on our site, share it with friends and make navigation more intuitive. To make your shopping easier and more enjoyable, AVADirect uses “cookies” to display and retain contents of your “shopping basket” while you browse the various sections of our online store. Your web browser places cookies on your hard drive for record-keeping purposes and to identify you should you visit the Site again. You may choose to set your web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you reject cookies, you may still use the Site but please note that some parts of the Site may be limited or not function properly. Our use of “cookies” is intended to provide you with a better experience when using the Site.

### How we use collected information

**We collect and use our Users' information for the following purposes:**

  * **_To run and operate our Site and other services_**

We use your information and share it with select third parties in order to display content on the Site correctly and to otherwise make the Site function properly. We also use your information and share it with select third parties in order to maintain and develop the Site and in connection with other services we provide.

  * **_To improve customer service_**

Information you provide helps us respond to customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.

  * **_To research our services_**

We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site and to evaluate the effectiveness of the Site and our marketing and business efforts.

  * **_To improve our Site_**

We use User information and feedback and share it with select third parties to improve our products and services.

  * **_To send Users information they agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to them._**

We use User information and share it with select third parties on an ongoing basis to share details, news, and marketing information about our services and the services of select third parties.

  * **_To send periodic emails_**

We may use your email address to send you information and updates or to respond to your inquiries, questions, and/or other requests.

We may also disclose any collected information, including personally identifiable information, if: (1) the disclosure is necessary or useful to our provision of services; (2) we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, interests, or property; (3) we are acting in good faith to protect your safety or the safety of others, to investigate fraud, or to respond to a government request; (4) we believe in good faith the disclosure is required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, search warrant, court order, or similar legal or administrative process; and (5) a third party purchases or otherwise acquires us or the Site, in which case your information will likely be among the assets transferred.

### How we protect your information

We have adopted appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to help protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored in connection with our Site.

### Transaction Security

AVADirect recognizes your right for privacy and full confidentiality while shopping online. All sensitive data such as billing and shipping information are securely encrypted using Secure Socket Layers (SSL) encryption protocol. AVADirect is committed to providing an up-to-date secure environment for online consumers. Therefore, the AVADirect.com web site is registered with independent site identification authorities. Trustwave Global Certificate Authority (CA) confirms both parties’ identities before any transmission is sent and the Trustwave SSL Certificate helps give all parties the confidence that information is being sent securely and to the right place.

### Fraud Protection

For your online shopping, AVADirect is committed to data security and protects the privacy of your credit card information, name, address, e-mail and any other information you provide via stringent controls.

  * We strongly encourage all shipments are processed only to the verified billing address as a measure to minimize risk of fraud credit card usage. 
  * For Customer purchases made with a credit card, AVADirect will only ship product to the verified billing address or an authorized shipping address that is registered with the Customer's credit card. (With proper customer authorization, alternative shipping addresses, other than the billing address, can be registered with credit card companies. Contact your credit card company for further information.) 
  * If you are more comfortable contacting our sales representatives direct, versus an online purchase, please call AVADirect at 1-866-766-4629 and we will gladly assist and process your order. 

Should you have any questions regarding our procedures, please contact us at 1-216-503-6374.

### Sharing your personal information

In addition to the uses and disclosures described above, we may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes.

### Electronic newsletters

If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include AVADirect news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via the contact information listed below.

### Third party websites

Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these other websites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies, including the privacy policy.

### Changes to this privacy policy

We have the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

### Children’s Privacy

The Site is not designed to solicit or collect data from individuals under the age of 13. In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we do not knowingly collect or store any personal information, even in aggregate, about children under the age of 13\. If we discover we have received any information from a child under the age of 13 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information within a reasonable time. If you believe that we have any information from or about anyone under the age of 13, please contact us at the contact points specified below.

### Controlling and Updating Your Personally Identifiable Information

If you believe that the Site contains information about you that needs to be updated or corrected, you can update that information by contacting us at the contact information below.

### Your California Privacy Rights

Under California’s "Shine the Light" law, California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us once a calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2013 will receive information regarding 2012 sharing activities).

To obtain this information in connection with information collected through the Site, please click here to send a message with "Request for California Privacy Information" in the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you at your e-mail address in response.

### California Do Not Track Disclosures

We do not collect personally identifiable information about users’ online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services. For this reason, at this time, the Site does not respond to “do not track” signals. Third parties may collect personally identifiable information through the Site as described in this Privacy Policy.

### Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, please click here to contact us.

_This document was last updated on September 9, 2016._
